Vipul Dev

Laxmi Niwas , Heingane Home Colony , Karve Nagar, Pune ,Maharashtra

9955838471 | devvipul911@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vipul-dev-8b371a1a2

Objective

I am a highly driven professional having 6 months of experience in LinkedIn based digital marketing and neich business development domain, with a demonstrated history of creating and executing successful marketing and business development strategies. Showed a track record of 30% increase in customer retention and acquisition with 20% spike in the conversion rate from prospects to leads . My goal is to get as much as exposure to marketing and business development practices in an organisation where I can polish my skills to optimise my professional journey as marketing and business development expert.

Experience

The Career Council

5/06/2023 - 5/09/2023

Marketing and research intern

I worked as a marketing and research intern in which my role was mainly for LinkedIn Optimization integrated with company branding and generating leads for business opportunities.

nCircle tech (Ongoing)

8/01/2024 - 8/04/2024

Business development intern

I have been working in the organisation for the past 2 months and my major role is to hunt clients and prospects so as to optimise the business opportunities of the company.

Projects

- Internship at The Career Council: Led a project to boost student engagement in affiliated academies.
 - Introduced weekly webinars featuring industry experts on various professional development topics. (Platforms: LinkedIn, Zoom, Google Meet)
 - Launched a placement assistance program connecting students with agencies, recruiters & HR professionals. (Platforms: LinkedIn, Naukri.com, Indeed.com, Glassdoor, Hirect)
 - Provided guidance on resume/LinkedIn profile improvement, interview skills & communication enhancement.
 - Initiatives resulted in a 20% increase in student engagement in attending regular classes and a 30% overall performance improvement.
- Internship at nCircle Tech: Built a strong sales pipeline through strategic prospecting for
 - Targeted key industries: AEC (Architectural, Engineering, Construction) & Manufacturing
 - Researched & identified decision-makers of the above mentioned industries using LinkedIn Sales Navigator tool .
 - Effective prospecting through decision makers profile reviewing considering their designation, years of experience, departments and recent activities.
 - Gathered approx 2000+ prospects with effective filtering for further qualification and proposal .
 - Reached out to the decisions maker through effective communication channels like cold emailing, cold calling and Linkedin personal note invitation.
 - Some notable pipelines I constructed included:
 - Sydney Build Expo 2024
 - Digital Construction Australia 2024
 - AMC Bridge US 2024
 - BAU Muenchen 2024 (World's leading architecture trade fair)
 - Singapore Expo 2024
 - The Pipelines showed increased conversion rate of prospects to leads by 30%.

Education

• Institute of management and entrepreneurship development (IMED), Pune, Maharashtra BBA - IB specialization (ongoing)

 Indian Institute of Aircraft Engineering (IIAE), Dwarka sec-8, New-Delhi Aircraft Maintenance Engineering (licensed Course)
70 % (last sem) 2018-2020

D.A.V public school, sec -4, Bokaro Steel City, Jharkhand
12 Class Board, Intermediate
75% (Science Stream)

2018

Skills

- Personal and professional skills -:
- · Decision making
- Problem solving
- · Critical thinking
- · LinkedIn Optimization
- · Ms office
- · Chatgpt prompt engineering
- · Bard AI (Gemini) prompt engineering

Achievements & Awards

- · Younity certificate of Excellence in personality development and soft skills building.
- · LinkedIn training program
- · Internship completion certificate

Languages

- English
- Hindi
- Bengali

Interests

- Playing chess- Competed with upto 2000 chess.com rating players .
- · Playing football For the past 1 year
- Working out in gym For the past 3 years
- Watching documentaries and movies on different topics. Favourites- Taxi driver, The last dace, Decoding bills brain, The Minimalist
- · Playing Carrom board